Animation Number 1
Sengoku Nadeko: 14 years old.
（千石(せんごく)）
千石撫子(なでこ) 14歳
Birthday: June 3rd.
６月３日生まれ
Gemini. Blood type B.
双子座 Ｂ型
Height: 153 cm.
身長 153センチ
Weight: 38 kg, more or less.
体重38キロ プラスマイナス
The world is difficult in many ways,
Animation Number 4
and nothing ever works out the way you think it will.
Animation Number 5
There are countless things you hate,
Animation Number 6
and the seeds of anguish...
Animation Number 7
Right-handed.
右利き
Eyesight: 20/10 in both eyes.
視力 左右ともに2,0
Parents: Alive and well.
両親 健在
Allowance: 1200 yen per month.
お小遣い 月に1200円
School: Junior High 701. Currently in class 2-2.
公立七百一(ななひゃくいち)中学校 ２年２組所属
Attendance number 28.
出席番号 28番
Though it doesn't evaporate entirely,
Animation Number 9
what you considered your daily life
Animation Number 10
crumbles away before you realize it,
Animation Number 11
the routines you thought
Animation Number 12
you could rely on
Animation Number 13
no longer works,
Animation Number 14
and your body and soul
Animation Number 15
are worn out by it
Animation Number 16
so completely
Animation Number 17
that you suddenly sink to the ground.
Animation Number 18
Favorite food: Hamburger. Yakisoba.
好きな食べ物
“ハンバーグ 焼きそば”
Favorite manga: Stuff from the 80s.
好きな漫画 “80年代”
Favorite game genre: Retro.
好きなゲーム “レトロ”
Favorite music genre: Folk songs.
好きな音楽 “フォークソング”
Favorite color: Purple.
好きな色 “紫”
Favorite big brother: Koyomi-oniichan.
好きなおにいちゃん
“暦(こよみ)おにいちゃん”
In love with:
好きな人—
Sometimes I collapse in frustration,
Animation Number 20
but I can still persevere
Animation Number 21
as long as my love is strong.
Animation Number 23
If the person I love stands next to me,
I can stand strong
Animation Number 24
and walk proudly.
Animation Number 25
Araragi Koyomi
Animation Number 29
Araragi Koyomi.
Araragi Koyomi
Animation Number 29
阿良々木(あららぎ)暦
Araragi Koyomi
Animation Number 29
Animation Number 30
If a stranger saw me now, what would they think?
（千石）
知らない人が今の撫子を見たら
どう思うんだろうね
Sneaking around under the floor of a shrine... Would they think I was a thief?
神社の床下で
コソコソとしているだなんて
泥棒だとでも思うのかな
Who knows? But, more or less, all humans are like thieves.
（クチナワ）さあな
しかし 人間なんて多かれ少なかれ
みんな泥棒みたいなもんだろうよ
Each and every one of 'em only thinks about snatching others' entitlements.
どいつもこいつも
他人の利権をかすめ取ることしか
考えてねえ
Really?
そうかな？
Of course. You felt that more deeply than anyone else in this world the past few days, Nadeko-chan, no?
（クチナワ）そうだろうよ
それを撫子ちゃんは
この数日で誰より
世界中の誰よりも
深く思い知ったんじゃねえのか？
ああん？
But, I think a lot of people aren't like that.
（千石）
でも そうじゃない人も
いっぱい いると思うけれど
If you're gonna say so, you should probably say "There are many times they aren't like that."
（クチナワ）それを言うなら
そうじゃないときも
いっぱいあると言うべきだろうな
It just depends on who they are at what time.
そいつが どういうときに
どういうヤツなのかって
ことだけだろ
Good people can easily become bad, and bad people can easily become good.
善人だって たやすく悪人になるし
悪人だって たやすく善人になる
All the people you have had to deal with were like that.
お前が今まで相手取ってきた連中も
みんな そうだったろうが
忘れちまったのか　ああん？
You haven't forgotten, no?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
The pounding rain was disturbing our conversation,
Animation Number 48
but I knew what he meant.
Animation Number 50
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hey, Sengoku.
（阿良々木）よう 千石
I wanted you to chase me here.
Animation Number 55
What's wrong? Look over here, Sengoku.
どうした　こっちを見ろよ 千石
I wanted you to save me.
Animation Number 57
And
Animation Number 59
Animation Number 60
I'm here to exterminate you...
（阿良々木）殺しに来たぜ
I wanted to be exterminated
Animation Number 62
...Sengoku.
千石
Koyomi-oniichan says he is a vampire.
（千石）
暦おにいちゃんは
吸血鬼だといいます
But you know, looking at him now you could say the healing powers were broken.
しかし
その吸血鬼ゆえの回復力というのは
こうして見るかぎり
全くといっていいほど
発揮されていないようでした
Hey now, that's a bad way to put it, Nadeko-chan.
（クチナワ）
おいおい ひどい言いぐさだな
撫子ちゃん
The one who put this vampire guy in such a bad condition is you.
この吸血鬼のおにいちゃんを
ここまでひっどい目に遭わせたのは
お前じゃねえかよ
Poison works against vampires too.
吸血鬼にも毒は有効だからな
The fangs you pierced him with haven't been pulled out; they're still embedded in him.
お前が突き立てた牙は
抜けることなく
今も こいつを貫いたままなのさ
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Ah, that's how it was...
（千石）そっか　そうだっけ
Of course.
（千石）
だよね　そうなんだよね
That's how it was.
It was me. It was my fault.
撫子だった　撫子が悪いんだった
With no room for excuses.
言い訳の余地なく
With no room for extenuating circumstances.
情状酌量の余地なく
It was my fault
撫子が悪いんだった
Then... I have to fight properly.
じゃあ ちゃんと戦わないと
（忍(しのぶ)）フンッ
Hmph.
Looks like she's completely fallen to being an aberration, body and soul.
身も心も すっかり怪異(かいい)に
堕してしもうたという感じじゃのう
いや
No. In this case, should I rather say that she's ascended to being an aberration?
この場合はいっそ怪異に昇天したと
言うべきなのか
I finally understand why Hawaiian-shirt guy was so worried about this bangs-girl.
あのアロハ小僧が やけに
この前髪娘を気にかけとった理由が
ようやく分かったわい
いや
今や こやつは前髪娘ならぬ
No, she's not bangs-girl. She's snake-hair girl now.
蛇髪娘か
Hey, you.
おい お前様よ
Don't hesitate. This girl is no longer your sister's friend, nor an innocent underclassman.
ためらうなよ
今や この娘は
お前様の妹御(いもうとご)の友人でもなければ
いたいけな後輩でもない
She's an evil, fiendish, hopeless aberration.
邪悪で凶悪でどうしようもない
怪異じゃ
Nothing more than a lone snake.
ただの１匹の蛇じゃ
I already know that.
（阿良々木）
分かってるよ　そんなことは
She's my enemy—and your meal.
こいつは僕の敵で お前の食糧だ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Go ahead and eat her, Shinobu.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
食っていいぜ 忍
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I'm jealous.
（千石）
羨ましい
Actually, I wanted to be in that position.
本当は
撫子が その位置にいたかった
I don't understand.
Animation Number 103
I wanted to be at Koyomi-oniichan's side.
暦おにいちゃんの隣にいたかった
I don't understand.
Animation Number 105
パートナーでいたかった
I wanted to be his partner.
I don't understand——
Animation Number 107
But why is Nadeko...
なのに どうして撫子は
What am I?
Animation Number 109
Why am I...
私は
Why?
Animation Number 111
Why have I become Koyomi-oniichan's enemy?
暦おにいちゃんと
敵対しているのでしょうか
I hate you, Koyomi-oniichan!
（千石）
暦おにいちゃんなんて
大っ嫌いだよ！
（阿良々木）なっ！
Yee-haw! Hey now, you finally did it, Nadeko-chan.
（クチナワ）ヒャッハ〜！
おいおい ついにやっちまったな
撫子ちゃん
（阿良々木）ぐはっ
The heart of the man I loved
Animation Number 125
I'm sorry, it's just so funny
Animation Number 126
Now, now, really...
（千石）
いやいや 本当—
Why did things have to end up this way...
どうして こんなことに
なってしまったのでしょうか
Why?
どうして…
Nadeko Medusa         Part One
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Animation Number 129
The story traces back a thousand years.
（千石）
話は千年前に遡ります
Hikari
Super
express
Am I tracing it back too far? I figured.
遡り過ぎ… ですよね エヘヘッ
I'll just trace it back to the day which I can speak about from my own experience.
遡るのは
せいぜい撫子が自分の経験として
しゃべれる範囲
In other words, the day that I met Kuchinawa-san.
つまり クチナワさんと出会った
その日までにしておきます
31st  of  October
That day was October 31st. A Tuesday.
その日の日付は10月31日
火曜日のことでした
I'm always "depressed" in the morning.
朝は いつも憂鬱なのです
To be more descriptive, I'm always "depressed" on my way to school.
もっと具体的に言うと
通学路は いつも憂鬱なのです
There is no path to school that doesn't make me "depressed."
憂鬱でない通学路などありません
Ever since that day.
あの日以来
Ever since June.
あの６月以来
Empty
Parking
Spots
Whoa, look...
（扇(おうぎ)）おっと 危なっ
Look...
危な… ううっ
Emergency
Button
...out!
Fire
Hydrant
Sense          of  Fear
Animation Number 168
A-Are you all right?
だ… 大丈夫？
I'm fine!
（扇）平気！
（千石）うわ〜！
You're not hurt, are you, Sengoku-chan?
ケガはないかい？　千石ちゃん
んん？　どうしたい 千石ちゃん
What's wrong, Sengoku-chan? I thought I dodged pretty well there.
うまくかわした
つもりだったけれど
But did I graze a hair or something, contrary to my expectations?
あにはからんや
髪の毛１本くらい
かすっちゃってたかな？
If so, I'm sorry, so sorry, Sengoku-chan.
だとしたら
ごめんごめん 千石ちゃん
W-Why...
ど… どうして…
W-Why do you know...
ど… どうして 撫子の名前…
Why do you know... my name?
（千石）
どうして撫子の名前 知ってるの？
Sense of Faux-Pas
Animation Number 184
Oh... right!
ああ そうだ　しまった
Oops, I forgot that Sengoku-chan and I aren't acquainted yet.
まだ 私は
千石ちゃんとは知り合ってなかった
Oh, geez, I totally did this out of order.
（扇）ああ もう　順番間違えた
それもこれも八九寺(はちくじ)ちゃんが
なかなか見つからないから
This is all because Hachikuji-chan is quite hard to find.
That girl is all too irregular. What a nuisance.
イレギュラーすぎなんだよな
あの子は
とんだ はた迷惑だよ
Oh, what should I do...
ああ どうしよっかな
Nice to meet you, cute little lady! My name is Oshino Ougi.
はじめまして
かわいらしいお嬢さん
私は忍野(おしの)扇というんだよ
Sense of Improvisation
Animation Number 189
Oshino?
忍野？
Let's see, how should I laugh this off...
（扇）
ええっと
何てごまかせばいいのかな
For now, with this girl, just mentioning Araragi-senpai's name should do the trick, right?
とりあえず この子には
阿良々木先輩の名前を出しとけば
いいんだっけ？
Then, well... Sengoku-chan, I've heard about you from Araragi-senpai.
じゃあ えっと…
千石ちゃん
君のことは
阿良々木先輩から聞いていたんだよ
See, can't you tell from the uniform? I'm Araragi-senpai's underclassman.
ほら 制服を見れば分かるでしょ？
私は阿良々木先輩の後輩なんだ
I'm also Kanbaru-san's underclassman.
神原(かんばる)さんの後輩でもある
Not an under class manager, I'm an underclassman. I'm a first-year at Naoetsu High School.
コーパイじゃないよ 後輩だよ
直江津(なおえつ)高校の１年生だよ
Oh, no good. I totally screwed up from the outset.
ああ… ダメか
出だしで失敗しちゃったな
Oh well. The case about Sengoku-chan is basically a side story anyway.
まいっか
千石ちゃんの件って
基本的に番外編だし
It shouldn't end up like Tsubasa-senpai staying at the Hanekawas' house.
羽川(はねかわ)んところの
翼(つばさ)先輩みたいなことには
ならないだろう
Let's see...
えっと
I'm Oshino Meme's niece.
私はね
忍野メメのめいっ子なんだよ
I heard about you from my uncle as well. I heard you were a victim.
君のことは
叔父さんからも聞いていた
被害者の女の子なんだってね
I'm sure it was because Kaiki-san was involved...
貝木(かいき)さんが関わっていたせいでは
あるけれど
...but boy oh boy, it's rare to see someone who is purely the victim of an aberration.
怪異に関して
純然たる被害者というのも珍しい
However,
ただし
people can't be victims forever, Sengoku-chan.
人はいつまでも被害者でいられる
わけじゃないからね
千石ちゃん
People just have times when they're victims, and times when they're the wrongdoers.
被害者でいるときと
加害者でいるときがあるだけだ
Or are you still thinking of yourself... as a victim?
それとも 君は今でも　まだ
被害者のつもりなのかな？
No response, huh?
無反応か
Well, if you keep looking down and staying quiet like that, then yes, maybe you'll be able to remain the victim.
そうやって目を伏せて黙って
何も言わずにいれば
確かに被害者でい続けることが
できるのかもしれないけれど
But will it go well this time around?
果たして今回は
そう うまくいくのかな？
This time may just be the exception.
今回は例外…
かもしれないんだぜ
It's easy to be the victim. Everyone sympathizes with you and is all nice to you.
被害者って楽でいいもんね
みんな同情して
優しくしてくれるもん
There is the phrase "thinking little of victims," but that's just merely saying "wrongdoers are victims too."
被害者軽視なんて言葉も
あるけれど
あれも“加害者も被害者だ”って
言ってるだけだもんね
叔父さんは そういう考え方は
嫌いだったと思うけれど
My uncle, though, I think he hated that train of thought.
Well, it just may be that oftentimes the world only has victims.
まっ えてして世の中には
被害者しかいない
ということなのかもしれない
Lilac Scene
Animation Number 'none'
In other words, flip that again, and maybe you weren't purely a victim from the beginning, Sengoku.
ということは更に裏返して
千石ちゃんも最初から
あんまり純然たる被害者
というわけでもないのかも
And in this story, that may be just beginning to surface.
そして 今回の物語では
それがあらわになるのかもね
S-Story?
も… 物語？
Yeah.
Oh, wait, Sengoku-chan, you're not saying you think
まさか それとも千石ちゃん
君は自分が
まるっきり物語性のない
日常の中を生きているなんて
you're living a life that has no prospect of becoming an actual story, are you?
思っているわけでもないだろ？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
See ya!
あれ？
Huh?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
For some strange reason, I didn't think I was chatting for that long...
（千石）
なぜか不思議なことに
そんなに話し込んでいたつもりは
ないのに
...but then I realized what time it was, and a lot of time had passed.
気がつけば 結構 時間が
過ぎてしまっていたのです
How to put it...
なんというか
It was as if time was stolen from me.
まるで時間を盗まれたかのように
Animation Number 230
Anyway, I got to school. My arrival.
さておき 学校に到着しました
アライバルです
The accident with Ougi-san hadn't made me late.
扇さんとの交通事故は
撫子を遅刻させることは
ありませんでした
Nanahyakuichi Public Middle School / Entrance
Animation Number 234
Coiling around my hand, possessing me.
Animation Number 236
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Was that just me?
（千石）気のせいだったのかな
Animation Number 249
Yes, that's right. This was the current state of class 2-2.
（千石）
ええ そうなんですよね
それが
現在の２年２組のありさまでした
In other words, a "depressing" school life.
つまりは憂鬱な学校生活です
Animation Number 253
If you asked whose fault it was, it wasn't really anyone's fault.
誰のせいかと言われれば
別段
誰のせいでもないんですけれど
Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who  Who
If we were to have an anonymous vote where we  wrote the name of one person that caused all this...
強いて そんな事態を招いた
原因となる人物を
無記名の投票で１人選ぶとするなら
I think it would be unanimous. That con artist Kaiki Deishu-san.
満場一致で あの詐欺師さん
Kai
貝木泥舟(でいしゅう)さんということに
なるのだと思います
Kai
He's a safe bet!
Safe  Bet
Animation Number 255
当確です
Oh no, I talk about him as if we've met, but I've never met him.
あっ いえ
Shoo-in
知り合いみたいに
言っていますけれど
Shoo-in
撫子は
その人に会ったことはありません
Shoo-in
Kaiki            Deishuu
Animation Number 256
However, we're more than simple acquaintances.
ただ 知り合い以上です
If you leave out my family,
Animation Number 257
As for how we've interacted, he's super-important.
関わり方としては
Koyomi-oniichan
Animation Number 257
超重要人物 ＶＩＰ
といっていいでしょう
and Tsukihi-chan,
Animation Number 257
You could say he's a VIP,
then he's the one
Animation Number 257
who left the biggest impression
in my life.
Animation Number 257
since my life deviated greatly because of him.
だって 撫子の人生は
その人のせいで
大きく ずれてしまったのですから
It went off it's path, and then crumbled apart.
外れてしまい
崩れてしまったのですから
Animation Number 258
Oh, perhaps saying it like this makes me sound like the victim?
ああ こういうのが
被害者じみた物言いということに
なるのかな
That's not good. I'll correct myself.
いけない いけない　訂正します
I can't stomach these victim mentalities
Animation Number 259
It's the environment around me that deviated. What deviated and crumbled was...
ずれたのは撫子の周囲です
外れたのも崩れたのも
周囲であり 撫子ではないです
...the environment around me. It wasn't me.
Maybe
Animation Number 261
I'm getting sidetracked here a little,
Animation Number 262
It was back in June.
I'm getting sidetracked here a little,
Animation Number 262
６月のことです
I'm getting sidetracked here a little,
Animation Number 262
but I think this should be elaborated upon,
Kaiki-san targeted every junior high student in town.
Animation Number 262
but I think this should be elaborated upon,
貝木さんは
Animation Number 262
but I think this should be elaborated upon,
この町の中学生を
ターゲットにしました
but I think this should be elaborated upon,
Animation Number 262
so allow me to reminisce.
I will keep it brief.
Animation Number 262
It was a fraud scheme to sell fake magic charms to all those students.
不特定多数の中学生に
インチキなおまじないを
販売するという詐欺でした
The sum involved was clearly not that large a figure.
お金そのものは
大した金額では
はっきり言ってありません
It was the Kaiki-style business of small profits, quick returns.
貝木流 薄利多売の商売でした
A few kids splurged, and it became an issue.
いき過ぎた子も もちろんいて
What Happened
Animation Number 262
それが問題になって
That's why the Fire Sisters went on the move.
ファイヤーシスターズが
動いたのですけれども
A
ra
gi
A
ra
gi
A
ra
gi
A
ra
gi
What Happened Before
Animation Number 262
But after some time had passed...
What Happened Before
Animation Number 262
しかし それから
月日が経過してみると
What Happened Before
Animation Number 262
What Happened After
the real issue was that the majority of the frauds were so inexpensive people could pay with their allowances.
本当に問題になったのは
お小遣いでなんとかなる範囲の
問題視するほどではない
大半の詐欺のほうでした
Those of my classmates who couldn't perform the ritual
Animation Number 263
Basically, within the class...
要するに クラス内で
"Who likes who."
誰が誰のことを好きか
"Who hates who."
誰が誰のことを嫌いか
"What someone thinks of someone else."
誰が誰のことを どう思っているか
"What someone wants to do with someone else."
誰が誰のことを どうしたいか
...things like that; you could say "how everyone feels," something even worse than personal information,
という
そういう個人情報の枠さえ超えた
みんなへの思いみたいなものが
全て露見してしまったのです
had all "come out in the open."
When I found out
Animation Number 266
I'm sure you have an idea what happens after such a thing.
まあ そのあと
どういうことになるか
what they really thought of me
Animation Number 266
even though I felt
we were getting along——
Animation Number 266
大体 分かりますよね
And it is just a commonplace coincidence...
そして ただのありふれた
偶然なのですけれど
...but for some reason, the "magic charms" Kaiki-san sold were very popular amongst my classmates.
貝木さんが売り物にした
おまじないが
どうしてなのか
撫子のクラスでは
大流行してしまったのです
Uneventful.
Animation Number 270
A class where nothing happens.
Animation Number 272
A class where everyone pretends to sleep.
Animation Number 274
The result of that is the "depressing" school life I have now.
その結果が
今の憂鬱な学校生活です
Very strained. Very gloomy.
ギスギスして モヤモヤして
Nobody can talk from their heart. A class that is only superficially peaceful.
誰も本心からの会話のできない
うわべだけが平和なクラス
Animation Number 288
A snake?
（電話:阿良々木）
蛇？
A snake, huh? The same as last time?
蛇な… 前のときの蛇か？
A delicate response
Animation Number 290
No, that's not it. It's different.
ううん
そうじゃなくて 違くって
I can't talk properly.
Animation Number 291
For now, there hasn't been any actual harm, right?
（電話:阿良々木）
今のところ
実害はないって感じなのか？
Nothing like last time when it started constricting your body, right?
それこそ前みたいに
お前の体を締めつけてるとか
そういうことは？
N-Nope.
（千石）う… うん　ないよ
Can you think of any causes?
（電話:阿良々木）
思い当たる原因は？　何かあるか？
A cause?
原因？
For hallucinations of white snakes to show up again and again around you...
（電話:阿良々木）
そんなふうに 白い蛇の幻覚が
お前の周囲に何度も何度も現れる
きっかけなのか何なのか
Can you think of anything familiar that started it?
身に覚えっつうのか
Familiar...
（千石）身に覚え…
I think on it.
Animation Number 298
Nothing comes to mind.
Animation Number 299
None at all...
ないけど
Hmm...
They say aberrations have reasons that are befitting.
怪異には それにふさわしい理由が
あるっていうけれど
Well, your case is slightly different. It was different last time too.
まあ
お前の場合はちょっと違うからな
前もそうだったし
For now, if it's not something urgent, let's wait until this evening.
Take telephone receiver
Press button
Dial a number
Neither coin nor card is needed
（電話:阿良々木）
まあ とりあえず
喫緊じゃねえってんなら
このまま夜を待つことにしようかな
Evening?
（千石）夜？
We should wait for Shinobu to wake up.
Philosophy
World History
（電話:阿良々木）
忍が起きるのを待つってことだ
あいつは最近
生活が規則正しいんだよ
She's pretty much got a regular body clock lately.
Shinobu didn't help us during the Jagirinawa incident...
蛇切縄(じゃぎりなわ)のときは
忍は協力してくれなかったけれど
今はあいつに
...but there's no way I can do without her help now.
力を貸してもらわないわけには
いかないし
Um, Shinobu... Shinobu-san eats aberrations, right?
（千石）えっと しの…
忍さんは怪異を食べるんだよね？
Then will she eat the white snake that I saw?
じゃあ撫子が見た白い蛇を…
食べるの？
Cooking
Childcare
Depends on the situation, but it's not like eating anything and everything is always the best course.
（電話:阿良々木）
場合によっては
でも 何でもかんでも
食べりゃいいってもんじゃねえから
So it's more about what she knows. Specialized information she inherited from old man Oshino.
必要なのは どちらかといえば
あいつの持ってる知識のほうだな
忍野のヤツから受け継いだ専門知識
Then... this evening?
（千石）じゃあ 夜
Yeah. Go home and wait for us. I'll call you.
（電話:阿良々木）
ああ　家に帰って待ってろ
電話するから
Let's see, Shinobu usually wakes up around 10 p.m., so plan on it being around then.
ええっと 忍が起きるのは
夜の10時くらいだから
そのころだと思っといてくれ
Okay, got it. Then, at 10 p.m.
（千石）うん 分かった
じゃあ 夜10時に
Blue Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I'll look forward to it.
Blue Scene
Animation Number 'none'
楽しみにしてるね
Blue Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I lowered my voice
Animation Number 326
Huh?
I lowered my voice
Animation Number 326
Oh,
Animation Number 329
damn.
A slip of the tongue.
Animation Number 329
Hey, Sengoku, are you all right?
（電話:阿良々木）
おい千石 大丈夫か お前
MG–3R Public Telephone
Mark 12345 First Edition
Serial Number 56789
Manufactured October 1878
Designed For 100V 110VA
Japanese Sound Telegraph Company LLC
You're looking forward to it? What are you saying? I thought you were in a crisis.
楽しみにしてるって
10 Yen / 100 Yen
No change given for 100 Yen coins
10 Yen coins will be used first
何 言ってんだ？
ピンチなんじゃなかったのか？
（千石）えっと…
Um...
I stay silent. I can't talk about it. I can't explain it.
Animation Number 330
1                2               3
When this light goes out,
please insert coins
Press      to call 110/119 at any time
Should I head over right now after all? You seem to be pretty confused...
（電話:阿良々木）
やっぱ 今すぐ行こうか？
なんかお前 混乱してるみたいだし
What you just said isn't good at all. You're looking forward to something involving aberrations...
ヤバいって 今の発言
怪異が絡んでる話を“楽しみ”とか
When in trouble,
Animation Number 332
N-No, that's not what I meant.
ち… 違うの　そうじゃなくて
it's a bad idea to apologize
Animation Number 334
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
in the hopes that this will solve it——
Animation Number 336
I'm sorry, Koyomi-oniichan.
ごめんなさい　暦おにいちゃん
If apologizing fixed anything,
Animation Number 337
No...
（電話:阿良々木）
いや 謝るようなことじゃないけど
nobody would need the police.
Animation Number 339
It's not something to apologize for...
That's what they say.
Animation Number 341
I'm all right. I'm fine.
（千石）大丈夫　大丈夫だから
That expression
Animation Number 342
I-In any case, this evening. W-Well...
と… とにかく夜に
え… えっと…
Um... at 10, right?
is a lot deeper
Animation Number 343
10時だよね？
When light flashes,
please insert card or coins
Hey, Sengoku.
（電話:阿良々木）
おい 千石
than anybody thinks.
Animation Number 346
M-My telephone card is running low. Oh, it's beeping!
（千石）テ… テレカ切れるから
わあ 音 鳴ってる
It's really beeping! It's going beep beep!
すごく音 鳴ってる
ピーピー 言ってる！
Return Slot
（ピピー ピピー）
Oh, come to think of it, I forgot to ask Koyomi-oniichan about Ougi-san.
ああ そういえば
扇さんのこと
暦おにいちゃんに聞くの忘れてたな
As I remember that for no coherent reason...
Animation Number 360
But... What is this phenomenon really?
でも 本当に何なんだろう この現象
It's strange.
（千石）
不思議です
Aberrations have reasons that are befitting.
怪異には
それにふさわしい理由がある
But this time, like the last, I can't think of anything that could be the reason.
だけど 今回も また
Telephone
Book
撫子には思い当たる節は
全くないのですから
Come now, you can't be serious, Nadeko-chan, no?
（クチナワ）
おいおい そりゃあ ねえだろ
撫子ちゃん
ああん？
You can't think of anything that could be the reason? That's taking things too far.
身に覚えがないだって
そりゃ あんまりってもんだぜ
Brats with no self-awareness like you are the most troublesome.
お前みたいな自覚のねえガキが
いちばん厄介(やっかい)なんだよ
Really... You don't know what you're stomping on to live at all.
まったく
自分が何を踏みにじって
生きてるんだか
まるっきり
分かってねえんだからよ
W-Who is it?
だ… 誰？
Snake
Come over to North Shirahebi Shrine, Nadeko-chan.
（クチナワ）
北白蛇(きたしらへび)神社に来な 撫子ちゃん
I'll teach you right there. About what you've been stomping on to keep living...
そこで教えてやるよ
お前が何を踏みにじって
生きているのかを
What's going on?
There are auditory hallucinations too now.
Animation Number 373
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
What happened to me?
What's wrong with me?
Animation Number 374
There is no such thing as a victim. Only wrongdoers exist in this world.
（クチナワ）
被害者なんて いねえんだよ
この世にいるのは加害者だけだ
Hearing Voices
Animation Number 372
Each and every person is full of misunderstandings.
どいつもこいつも
とんだ勘違い野郎ばかりだぜ
Animation Number 375
You're not surprised.
（クチナワ）
驚かねえんだよな？　お前は
As if it were obvious... As if you knew all along... Not even one scream...
分かりきっていたかのように
知り尽くしていたかのように
悲鳴を上げもしない
Right.
そう　だって
Because...
The one who created this nightmarish scene from hell...
この地獄絵図のような悪夢を
作り出したのは
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
...is none other than...
ほかならぬ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
....yourself.
お前自身なんだからな
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Nadeko-chan.
撫子ちゃん
I-I...
な… 撫子は…
I didn't go this far...
撫子は
ここまでのことは してないよ
Right. This is...
（クチナワ）そう これは
...just an illusion.
ただの幻覚
Let's see, was it about this many?
ええっと
これくらいの
数だったかい？
撫子ちゃん
How many you killed off, Nadeko.
お前がぶっ殺した数は
Slaughter.
Animation Number 401
Mutilation.
Crucified——Snakes.
Animation Number 401
You did go this far, right?
ここまでのことなら
したんだよな？
Maybe I could have cast down my eyes
Animation Number 406
and stood there quietly
Animation Number 408
to stay a victim——
Animation Number 410
I wonder if that would have worked out.
Animation Number 412
S-Snake...
へ… 蛇
If you want to atone for this sin, I'll give you the opportunity.
（クチナワ）もし お前が
この罪を償いたいと思うのなら
俺様は その機会をくれてやる
Take off that blindfold and look over here.
その目隠しを外して こっちを見な
Over here?
（千石）こっち？
You looked over here. You looked at me, Kuchinawa.
（クチナワ）こっちを見たな
このクチナワを見たな
In other words, you are now one of my compatriots. In other words, my partner.
つまり これで
お前も俺様の同胞ってわけだ
パートナーってわけだ
償ってもらうぜ
I'll have you atone, all right...
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
...Nadeko-chan.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
撫子ちゃん
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 429
W-What? S-Should I apologize? Do you want me to apologize?
（千石）な… 何？
あ… 謝ればいいの？
謝ってほしいの？
つ… 償うって何？
W-What do you mean by atone? I... I...
撫子は… 撫子は
何をすればいいの？
What should I do?
（クチナワ）
何をすればいいの… か
"What should I do," huh?
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Normally, in times like this, people ask for forgiveness.
普通 こういうときは
許しを請うものなんだけどな
許してくださいの
ひと言もないってのは
The fact that you didn't say "please forgive me" is really something!
大したもんだ
Massive Slaughter
Animation Number 433
I-I'm not that...
な… 撫子はそんな…
Attacker
Animation Number 434
Or maybe I shouldn't have used a roundabout word like "atone."
（クチナワ）あるいは 償いなんて
遠回しな言い方を
するべきじゃなかったかもな
It's been a while since I last spoke with a human, so I don't know how to set limits.
人間と話すのは久しぶりなもんで
加減が分かんねえんだ
Bad, bad... That was my bad, no?
悪い悪い 悪かったよ
ああん？
Well, I just have a favor to ask of you.
な〜に お願いがあるんだよ
俺様は撫子ちゃんに
If you feel any guilt about the fact that you killed off a dozen or so of my compatriots...
俺様の同胞を
十何匹だか殺したことを
少しでも撫子ちゃんが
気に病んでくれるなら
I want you to listen, just for a little bit, to the favors I ask of you.
（クチナワ）
ほんのちょっとだけ
俺様のお願いを聞いてほしいんだ
Favors...
（千石）お願い？
Or do you prefer me to put it like this, Nadeko-chan...
（クチナワ）
ああ それとも撫子ちゃんには
こういう言い方をすれば
いいのかな？
Please save me, Nadeko-chan.
助けてくれよ 撫子ちゃん
I thought he was asking for the impossible. But declining was even more impossible.
（千石）
無理な相談だと思いました
けれど 断るほうが より無理でした
Pink Scene
Animation Number 'none'
A-All right.
Pink Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（千石）
わ… 分かった
Pink Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I'll say it. Ears plugged, eyes downcast... I'll say it.
（千石）
撫子は言います
耳を塞ぎながら 目を伏せながら
J-Just for a little bit.
ちょ… ちょっとだけだからね
But come to think of it, the ending to this story was already determined back then.
（千石）
だけど 思えばこのときには
既にこの物語の結末は
決まっていたのでしょう
Even if I knew what Kuchinawa-san wanted me to do back then...
もしも このときに
クチナワさんが
撫子にやらせようとしていることを
知っていたとしても
Even if I knew what Kuchinawa-san wanted to do to me.
クチナワさんが撫子を
どうするつもりか
知っていたとしても
Even if I knew the truth and the facts.
真実と真実を知っていたとしても
I'm sure I would've nodded yes in the same way.
やっぱり撫子は
同じようにうなずいたでしょうから
So I think destiny would not have changed.
運命は変わらなかったと思います
A story as such is nothing but a story.
そういった物語は物語でしかなく
And the future where I fight Koyomi-oniichan to the death is inching ever closer.
暦おにいちゃんと殺し合う未来は
刻一刻と近づいています
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐(かれん)）火憐だぜ！
（月火(つきひ)）月火だよ
And Tsukihi!
I'm Tsukihi!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
Decoy
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
（火憐･月火）
２人合わせて
ファイヤーシスターズ！
What's wrong, Nadeko-chan?
Otorimonogatari has finally started!
（火憐）
ついに始まったな
囮(おとり)物語
（月火）
うん　主役はどうやら
The main character is dead to me though.
知らない人
みたいなんだけど
My little sister hates popular things!
（火憐）
私の妹
人気者が嫌いすぎるぜ
（月火）
予告編クイズ！
Preview Quiz!
（火憐）
クイズ！
Quiz!
If you mix 300L of a 5% saline solution with 300L of a 10% saline solution, you get 600L total.
（月火）
５パーセントの食塩水
300リットルに
10パーセントの食塩水
300リットルを
When I woke up this morning, my hair was like this...
Ew!
混ぜ合わせた
600リットルの食塩水に
Add to that 400L of a 20% saline solution then drink half of it, what volume at what concentration do you end up with?
20パーセントの食塩水
400リットルを
加えたものを半分飲むと
何パーセントの食塩水
何リットルに
なるでしょう？
What a serious quiz. You get 500L at 12.5% concentration, right?
（火憐）
マジのクイズじゃねえか
１２･５パーセントの食塩水
500リットルだろ？
Ah! Our brother always shows up at the worst times!
If anyone sees me
like this, I'll die!
The right answer was: you drank only half of it!
（月火）
正解は
〝半分も飲めない〞
でした！
（火憐）
ぶん殴りてえな
I'm gonna hit you.
Now, if you mix 100L of a 25% saline solution with 200L of a 25% saline solution,
25パーセントの食塩水
100リットルに
200リットルを
混ぜ合わせ
then let it evaporate until there is a quarter left, what volume at what concentration remains?
半分の半分になるまで
蒸発させれば
I got an idea...
Divination
Welcome.
何パーセントの食塩水
何リットルに
なるでしょう？
Since salt doesn't evaporate, you get 75L of a 100% saline solution.
（火憐）
蒸発なら
塩は減らないから
100パーセントの食塩水
75リットル？
That would be only salt.
（月火）
それは もはや塩だね
Only salt indeed.
（火憐）
それは もはや塩だろ
Next time! Otorimonogatari Episode 2!
Next Time
Nadeko Medusa Part 2
（火憐･月火）
次回「囮物語」第２話
Nadeko Medusa Part 2!
「なでこメドゥーサ
其ノ貳(そのに)」
Now, take 100L of a 50% saline solution...
Nadeko Snake Consultation!
Is that some kind of magic show?
50パーセントの食塩水
100リットルを…
I'm done solving these!
（火憐）
そんなに溶けねえよ